Louis Young

Software Engineer [Web | Mobile]

Rue du Maupas 33, Lausanne, Switzerland louisyoung420@gmail.com +41 225480193

A full-stack software engineer (**front-end** heavy) with a broad knowledge of **JavaScript** technologies and a creative **UI/UX** sense.

My career started in web development after graduating from university in 2015. Since then, I have been working on front-end programming for web and mobile applications for over **7 years** specializing in reactive JavaScript technologies, exclusively using React and Vue.js. Especially I am an old fan of **Vue.js** and **Nuxt.js**.

As an accomplished professional in cross-platform app development, I strongly prefer utilizing **lonic Framework** and **Capacitor**. My skill set includes full-stack development, focusing on utilizing **Node.js** and **Laravel** as backend technologies.

I have a passion for crafting **user-friendly interfaces** and optimizing **performance**. I maintain a **detail-oriented** and conscientious approach to my work, ensuring a high standard of **quality assurance**.

For more information: https://louisyoung.vercel.app

SKILLS

- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, TypeScript, PHP
- * TailwindCSS, Chakra UI, Material UI, Bootstrap, Vuetify
- React, Vue, Svelte, Solid, Ember, Remix, Next, Nuxt
- Redux, React Query, Mobx, Zustand, Vuex, Pinia, GraphQL, Web3, Ether.js, D3
- Ionic, Capacitor, Electron, Inertia.js, Quasar
- Jest, Testing Library, Cypress
- Firebase, Supabase, Node.js, Laravel, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- Nginx, Vercel, Netlify, Docker, Git

EXPERIENCE



sporttrax, United States - Full-stack Web & Mobile Engineer

NOVEMBER 2022 - PRESENT

Vue | Inertia | TypeScript | Pinia | Ionic | Capacitor | Laravel | MySQL | Redis | Pusher | TailwindCSS | Electron

Projects: meettrax (Web, Mobile, Desktop)

- Was responsible for rewriting Laravel endpoints, controllers, and views to make seamless client-server communication with Inertia.js
- Used an optimistic update strategy for all Pinia mutations to provide lightning-fast request feedback to users
- Adopted customized caching strategy with Pinia store
- Composed mobile UI components crafted from Ionic components and TailwindCSS
- Built utility functions for global use using Ionic APIs
- Built meettrax mobile app from prototype to deployment as a sole developer



Zebedee, United States - Front-end Web & Mobile Engineer

OCTOBER 2021 - OCTOBER 2022

React | React Native | Redux | TypeScript | Redux | Jest | Mixpanel | Node

Projects: <u>Developer Dashboard</u>, <u>ZBD App</u>, <u>ZBD Browser Extension</u>

- Refactored entire CSS code with styled-components to implement dynamic UI elements
- Developed core functionalities such as Bitcoin lightning invoicing
- Simplified codebase and improved productivity for future development by swapping legacy Redux store for ReduxToolkit
- Owned product analytics feature utilizing Mixpanel
- Composed unit testing code with React Testing Library and Jest
- Contributed to ZBD mobile app by building some mobile pages with React Native



<u>Interchain Foundation</u>, Switzerland - *Front-end Software Engineer*

APRIL 2020 - AUGUST 2021

Vue | Nuxt | TypeScript | Web3 | Netlify | Laravel

Projects: Cosmos Network's official website

- Translated the design team's UI/UX wireframes and mockups into well-organized and component-driven code
- Optimized performance by minimizing payload, code-splitting, lazy-loading, memoization/caching, and image optimization
- Rewrote all Pinia-based state management codes using an optimistic update strategy
- Strategically migrated legacy JavaScript codebase to TypeScript



Twenty Labs, United States - Web & Mobile Developer

MARCH 2017 - FEBRUARY 2020

React | TypeScript | Next.js | Redux | Ionic | Capacitor | Swiper | Chart.js | D3 | Cypress | Node | Prisma | PostgreSQL | Socket.io | ElasticSearch

Projects: <u>Healthy Together</u> (Web, Mobile)

- Refreshed UI with new Figma design for both web and mobile
- Modularized components and reorganized Redux store by modules
- Implemented core modules while closely working with the QA team and promptly reflecting feedback from various clients and business objectives
- Spearheaded mobile app development with Ionic, React, Capacitor
- Automated real-time notification with Socket.io in Node.js backend
- Implemented e2e testing with Cypress.io
- Developed CRM dashboard for data analysis and visualization (jQuery, Chart.js, Google Map)
- Accelerated search capabilities by integrating ElasticSearch into the application.
- Data visualization with D3



Antinomy Studio, Netherlands - Web Developer

JUNE 2016 - MARCH 2017

Vue | Nuxt | Vuex | Stripe | GSAP | PWA | Laravel

Projects: <u>Blok Watches</u>

- Applied server-side rendering and static-side generation and increased SEO with Nuxt.js
- Translated approved designs into a fully functional website with Vuex store
- Built adorable CSS animations and GSAP animations
- Integrated Stripe's checkout platform to facilitate secure payments for customers.

EDUCATION



Hong Kong University of Science and Technology (HKUST)

Bachelor of Science (BS), Computer science

SEPTEMBER 2011 - SEPTEMBER 2015